# **Andy Chen**

Rich experience in full-stack software engineering with full product life-cycle and open source contribution. I care about user experience as much as internal/external developer experience, with multiple experiences in working with a cross-functional team.

amazingandyyy@gmail.com github.com/amazingandyyy https://amazingandyyy.com linkedin.com/in/amazingandyyy

### **EXPERIENCE**

Minted LLC, San Francisco — Senior Software Engineer March 2019 - PRESENT

- Work at software architecture team to improve internal tooling and speed up automation pipelines by 5 times.
- Author internal protobuf development process from building, compiling, testing to deploying, distribution and migration, mainly in leverage GNU make, shell scripts and dockers.
- Maintain and build kafka python client library, beam/flink pipeline.

<u>Blockchain Node Service Inc.</u>, San Francisco — *Founder and Project Lead Developer* July 2018 - PRESENT

- Leverage Docker, AWS CloudFormation to speed up the full-node initial process, successfully decrease the usual full-node hosting DevOps from 3 weeks to 15 seconds.
- Distribute stable service globally with CloudFront and Route53, successfully cut server usage by 60% and decreased responding time by 50%.
- Develop a serverless, stateless architecture to deliver the first-of-its-kind full-node monitoring service and won the top 3 as "the most fundable project" on Draper Demo day in Fall 2018.

**Bodhi Project**, San Mateo— *Senior Software Engineer* May 2018 - Oct. 2018

- Refactored the whole React UI library from redux to mobX architecture in 4 weeks and successfully initiated the migration from electron-based to browser-based DApp which ultimately led to an increase in usage by 2 times.
- Developed and audited production-ready complex solidity smart contracts on QTUM blockchain.
- Introduced style-checking linter and coordinated with teammates to improve the collaboration cycle and speed up the development process.
- Built the prototype of ginfura, a full node service for QTUM ecosystem.

<u>Ventured International Inc.</u>, San Mateo — *Lead Engineer turned Chief Product Officer* July 2017 - April 2018 (company resolved)

 Co-authored whitepaper, designed and developed the end-to-end DApp from zero-to-one in less than a month. Implemented TDD with Jest to engineer production-ready smart contracts in Solidity and deployed to

### **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

Backend: **RESTful/GraphQL Beam/Flink, grpc/protobuf**express.js, MongoDB/SQL,
Next.js, SSR, SEO, JWT

DevOps: NPM/nexus,
Docker/K8S, TravisCI/Jenkins,
CircleCI, Truffle, AWS CSAA,
GNU make, unix shell

Languages: Javascript, **Nodejs**, **Golang**, Python, **Solidity, bash** 

Front-End: html/css/sass, Javascript, **React/Redux**, **MobX**, Gulp, **Webpack**, **RWD** 

## OPEN SOURCE CONTRIBUTIONS

**use-form-react,** a react form hook made building form use in any react app.

**mern,** open source mern stack boilerplate repo and with over 1K downloads and clones.

nodejs/node, submitted
PR#10092[merged] and
#10093[merged] to update and
improve testing environment

dawsbot/mailto, submitted PR#3[closed], PR#4[merged] to resolve multiple issues and optimize key features

- Ethereum Live Network with Truffle framework.
- Developed an ERC-20 compatible VentureCoin(VCN) token and successfully launched a 3-month crowd-sale in November 2017.

### **Yeah Education Group,** Berkeley — Lead Engineer Dec. 2015 - April 2017

 Led a cross-timezone development team to migrate the full-stack app from angular 1.6 to React 15 in 3 months and migrate RESTful API to GraphQL hybrid API. Successfully scaled the business 20 times to 2M annual revenue in 2016 and led the company to join Berkeley-owned Skydeck incubator and push the company to become UC Berkeley's only official admission partner.

### <u>Andysign Studio</u>, Mountain View — *Freelance Web Developer* Oct 2014 - Sept. 2016

- Coordinated with 8 clients to develop websites including Groove Trend and Swallet, and Taiwanese Volunteer Group with about 1K daily visitors.
- Implemented A/B testing for UI elements, heatmap analysis on user behaviors and website SEO leading to a 100% increase in traffic and earned a full satisfaction rate from clients.

### **EDUCATION**

# <u>University of California, Berkeley</u>, Berkeley — *Bachelor's of Science, Cognitive Science* June 2016 - July 2018

The first and only student completing all 3 blockchain courses (Blockchain for Developers, Blockchain Lab, Blockchain Fundamental). Certificate in Entrepreneurship & Technology from SCET and served as Tech Chair in Senior Class Council 18. Completed courses included Data Vis., Computer HCI, Cognitive Science, Linguistics, Data Structure, Discrete Math and Machine Learning.

## <u>Draper University</u>, San Mateo — *Certificated Startup Hero* Sept 2018 - Oct 2018

Grown <u>venode</u> project into <u>BNS</u> and graduated as top 3 of "the most fundable project" voted by hundreds of VCs on Demo Day. Completed full Hero Training Program and was nominated as "the most positive student" by Tim Draper.

### **PROJECTS**

### **<u>Leptin</u>** — A PoW cryptocurrency implement in Nodejs

Designed and built a whole cryptocurrency in Nodejs with leveraging the power of WebRTC, LevelDB, hyperlogs to build a peer-to-peer blockchain implementing Proof-of-work, secp256k1 and dynamical difficulty.

### **Etherbrite** — An Eventbrite-like DApp.

Built a DApp in Solidity, TruffleJS, Web3js and React/Redux. From deploying events on smart contract to register and check-in.

#### HACKATHONS/AWARDS

H4YT Blockchain Hackathon 2018 - **No.1 nomination by Cosmos** for building <u>Celadon</u>, a lotionjs middleware donating money to help our environment.

LAUNCH Hackathon 2016 - 1st place of Uber Challenge for building <u>Teleport</u>, an advertisement site that connects customers and business.

AT&T IoT Hackathon - **Best Mobile App and IoT Solution Overall**[2015] for building

Connect, a radio player

controlled with Myo gesture

controller.

### MENTORSHIP/BLOG

### **Distributed Tech Salon**

authored a technical blog sharing a series of tutorials on web dev, smart contract, DevOps and Arc. design topics.

<u>**DIDX/Vechain Community**</u> <u>**Group**</u> on **Github** I founded virtual organization on Github to discuss topics of developer experience and developer tools.

NodeSchool Oakland and San Francisco Chapter Served as regular monthly mentor in Nodeschool Oakland

**Reactathon, 2017** Served as a mentor at the hackathon held by the Real World React organization